<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>version control | FAKIN</title>
    <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/version-control/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/version-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>version control</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2019 [Kompetenzzentrum Wasser Berlin gGmbH](https://www.kompetenz-wasser.de)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:35:15 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>version control</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/version-control/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Science MOOC</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:35:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/mooc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Research is getting a global makeover, in part thanks to the power of the internet and the tools it provides for us, and in part due to a growing call for accountability (e.g., reproducibility and data provenance) in research. Global policies are emerging at different levels that include some aspect of Open Research, Open Scholarship, or Open Science, and inclusive of all research disciplines. But our universities are often letting us down, and they are not teaching us the knowledge, tools and skills we need to do research effectively in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Science is about increased rigour, accountability, reproducibility for research. It is based on the principles of inclusion, fairness, equity, and sharing. Open Science can be viewed as research simply done properly, and it extends across the Life and Physical Sciences, Engineering, and Mathematics, to Social Science and Humanities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This MOOC is designed to help equip students and researchers with the skills they need to excel in a modern research environment. It brings together the efforts and resources of hundreds of researchers and practitioners who have all dedicated their time and experience to create a community platform to help propel research forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of this MOOC will be distilled into 10 core modules. Each module will comprise a complete range of resources including videos, research articles, dummy datasets and code, as well as tasks to complete as individuals or groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MOOC will be hosted through an open source provider. We expect that in the future different systems of certification will be developed, including completion badges. We also intend to build a forum for the open discussion of the MOOC and any relevant topics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensciencemooc.eu/about/&#34;&gt;opensciencemooc.eu, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Git is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to
handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency.
Git is easy to learn and has a tiny footprint with lightning fast performance.
It outclasses SCM tools like Subversion, CVS, Perforce, and ClearCase with
features like cheap local branching, convenient staging areas, and multiple
workflows.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git-scm.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gitlab is a collaborative code repository. It is used as backup mirror for our &lt;a href=&#34;fakin/tool/github/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; code repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datacamp</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/datacamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn Data Science from the comfort of your browser, at your own pace with
DataCamp&#39;s video tutorials &amp;amp; coding challenges on R, Python, Statistics &amp;amp; more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://datacamp.com&#34;&gt;DataCamp, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;GitHub Inc. is a web-based hosting service for version control using Git. It is
mostly used for computer code. It offers all of the distributed version control
and source code management (SCM) functionality of Git as well as adding its own features. It provides access control and several collaboration features such as
bug tracking, feature requests, task management, and wikis for every project.
GitHub offers plans for enterprise, team, pro and free accounts which are
commonly used to host open-source software projects. From January 2019, GitHub
now offers unlimited private repositories to all plans, including free accounts.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GitHub&#34;&gt;Wikipedia, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub can be integrated with &lt;a href=&#34;../zenodo/&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/activities/citable-code/&#34;&gt;making your code citable&lt;/a&gt;
and also for long-term storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subversion</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/svn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Version Control System for (internally) tracking source code (R scripts).
For developing R Packages we use &lt;a href=&#34;../github/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.) for version control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
