<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming | FAKIN</title>
    <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/programming/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>programming</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2019 [Kompetenzzentrum Wasser Berlin gGmbH](https://www.kompetenz-wasser.de)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>programming</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/programming/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Git is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to
handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency.
Git is easy to learn and has a tiny footprint with lightning fast performance.
It outclasses SCM tools like Subversion, CVS, Perforce, and ClearCase with
features like cheap local branching, convenient staging areas, and multiple
workflows.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git-scm.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executable Research Compendia</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/erc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/erc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open access is not only a form of publishing such that research papers become available to the large public free of charge, it also refers to a trend in science that the act of doing research becomes more open and transparent. When science transforms to open access we mean access to papers, research data being collected, data being generated, access to the procedures carried out in the research paper, even to the computational environment that was used, in order to reproduce and inspect the findings in the paper.Reproducibility of research findings, the ability to repeat experimental procedures and confirm previously found results, is at the heart of the scientific method. For many sciences the reproduction involves the replication of an experimental set up, e.g. in the lab or a field mission to collect data. Increasingly, scientific results are generated by numerical manipulation of data that were already collected, and may involve simulation experiments that are completely carried out computationally.In this proposal Opening Reproducible Research (ORR) we directly aim for the main aspects of open access, by improving the exchange of, by facilitating productive access to and by simplifying reuse of research results that are published over the Internet. The experimentally oriented proposal ORR aims at both the publication process (technische und organisatorische Aspekte des Publikationsprozesses) and the reuse of publications (Absichern der möglichst umfassenden Nachnutzbarkeit der Publikationen), but combines these goals by setting a clear innovation in the area of reproducible research, a goal that has extraordinary meaning for scientific publication. Central to the proposal is a new form for creating and providing research results, the executable research compendium (ERC), which not only enables third parties to reproduce the original research and hence recreate the original research results (figures, tables), but also facilitates interaction with them and the recombination of them with new data or methods. The container format that specifies the ERC will store all information required by different applications (e.g. one-click reproduce, long-term archive, research information systems, discovery purposes) and thus guarantees use independent from original information systems. Building on existing open standards and software, this project will develop standards and tools for ERCs and demonstrate and evaluate these based on fully fledged case studies, initially taken from the geosciences domain. ORR will make a step forward towards executable papers as a new standard in scientific publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uni-muenster.de/Geoinformatics/en/research/projects/O2R.html&#34;&gt;o2r project, WWW Muenster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeOcean</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/codeocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/codeocean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Our mission is to make the world&#39;s scientific code more reusable, executable and reproducible
Code Ocean is a cloud-based computational reproducibility platform that provides researchers and developers an easy way to share, discover and run code published in academic journals and conferences.
More and more of today&#39;s research includes software code, statistical analysis and algorithms that are not included in traditional publishing. But they are often essential to reproducing the research results and reusing them in a new product or research. This creates a major roadblock for researchers, one that inspired the first steps of Code Ocean as part of the 2014 Runway Startup Postdoc Program at the Jacobs Technion Cornell Institute.
For the first time, researchers, engineers, developers and scientists can upload code and data in any open source programming language and link working code in a computational environment with the associated article for free. We assign a Digital Object Identifier (DOI) to the algorithm, providing correct attribution and a connection to the published research.
Phyton
R
Julia
Matlab
Octave
C++
Fortran
Perl
Java
Lua
Stata&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform provides open access to the published software code and data to view and download for everyone for free. But the real treat is that users can execute all published code without installing anything on their personal computer. Everything runs in the cloud on CPUs or GPUs according to the user needs. We make it easy to change parameters, modify the code, upload data, run it again, and see how the results change.
We&#39;re excited to be on this mission to make scientific code more open. We hope you&#39;ll join us!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeocean.com/about&#34;&gt;CodeOcean, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gitlab is a collaborative code repository. It is used as backup mirror for our &lt;a href=&#34;fakin/tool/github/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; code repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codecov</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/codecov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/codecov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Develop healthier code. Improve your code review workflow and quality. Codecov
provides highly integrated tools to group, merge, archive, and compare coverage
reports.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codecov.io/&#34;&gt;Codecov.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mybinder</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/mybinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/mybinder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn a Git repo into a collection of interactive notebooks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Have a repository full of Jupyter notebooks? With Binder, open those notebooks
in an executable environment, making your code immediately reproducible by anyone,
anywhere.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mybinder.org&#34;&gt;mybinder, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datacamp</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/datacamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn Data Science from the comfort of your browser, at your own pace with
DataCamp&#39;s video tutorials &amp;amp; coding challenges on R, Python, Statistics &amp;amp; more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://datacamp.com&#34;&gt;DataCamp, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appveyor</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/appveyor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/appveyor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continious integration for Windows (free for public repositories)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travis-CI</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/travis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;GitHub Inc. is a web-based hosting service for version control using Git. It is
mostly used for computer code. It offers all of the distributed version control
and source code management (SCM) functionality of Git as well as adding its own features. It provides access control and several collaboration features such as
bug tracking, feature requests, task management, and wikis for every project.
GitHub offers plans for enterprise, team, pro and free accounts which are
commonly used to host open-source software projects. From January 2019, GitHub
now offers unlimited private repositories to all plans, including free accounts.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GitHub&#34;&gt;Wikipedia, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub can be integrated with &lt;a href=&#34;../zenodo/&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/activities/citable-code/&#34;&gt;making your code citable&lt;/a&gt;
and also for long-term storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demoware</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/project/demoware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/project/demoware/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subversion</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/svn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Version Control System for (internally) tracking source code (R scripts).
For developing R Packages we use &lt;a href=&#34;../github/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.) for version control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rstudio</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/rstudio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;RStudio is an integrated development environment (IDE) for &lt;a href=&#34;../r/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/&#34;&gt;RStudio, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/r/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
