<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python | FAKIN</title>
    <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/python/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>python</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2019 [Kompetenzzentrum Wasser Berlin gGmbH](https://www.kompetenz-wasser.de)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>python</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tags/python/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datacamp</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/code/datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/code/datacamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R package for checking &lt;a href=&#34;../../tool/datacamp/&#34;&gt;Datacamp&lt;/a&gt; use at KWB. It also provides an overview on available courses, skill and career tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeOcean</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/codeocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/codeocean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Our mission is to make the world&#39;s scientific code more reusable, executable and reproducible
Code Ocean is a cloud-based computational reproducibility platform that provides researchers and developers an easy way to share, discover and run code published in academic journals and conferences.
More and more of today&#39;s research includes software code, statistical analysis and algorithms that are not included in traditional publishing. But they are often essential to reproducing the research results and reusing them in a new product or research. This creates a major roadblock for researchers, one that inspired the first steps of Code Ocean as part of the 2014 Runway Startup Postdoc Program at the Jacobs Technion Cornell Institute.
For the first time, researchers, engineers, developers and scientists can upload code and data in any open source programming language and link working code in a computational environment with the associated article for free. We assign a Digital Object Identifier (DOI) to the algorithm, providing correct attribution and a connection to the published research.
Phyton
R
Julia
Matlab
Octave
C++
Fortran
Perl
Java
Lua
Stata&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform provides open access to the published software code and data to view and download for everyone for free. But the real treat is that users can execute all published code without installing anything on their personal computer. Everything runs in the cloud on CPUs or GPUs according to the user needs. We make it easy to change parameters, modify the code, upload data, run it again, and see how the results change.
We&#39;re excited to be on this mission to make scientific code more open. We hope you&#39;ll join us!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeocean.com/about&#34;&gt;CodeOcean, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datacamp</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/tool/datacamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn Data Science from the comfort of your browser, at your own pace with
DataCamp&#39;s video tutorials &amp;amp; coding challenges on R, Python, Statistics &amp;amp; more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://datacamp.com&#34;&gt;DataCamp, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E(R)lernen auf Datacamp</title>
      <link>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/post/kwb-datacamp-group-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kwb-r.github.io/fakin/post/kwb-datacamp-group-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seit heute hat das KWB auf der Online Programmierplattform &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt; ein kostenpflichtes Gruppenkonto mit 5 Plätzen abonniert, dass das e**&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;**lernen
nochmals verbessern dürfte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bisher gab es zwar schon eine KWB Gruppe auf &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt;,
jedoch mussten Interssierte für die kostenpflichtigen Kurse jeweils ein monatliches
Abo für Datacamp abschließen und sich die Kosten dann nachträglich wieder vom KWB
erstatten zu lassen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Es gilt folgender Workflow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Werde Mitglied in unserer kostenfreien &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com/groups/r-kwb&#34;&gt;R@KWB DataCamp Gruppe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; indem du den folgenden &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com/groups/3a6e6d4a7314de1b56a33c99c457b5c7eca00f6a/invite&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;
klickst. Wenn du noch kein DataCamp Account hast, registiere dich bitte unter Angabe
deiner KWB Emailadresse. Die Mitgliedschaft in dieser Gruppe dient zweierlei.
Zum einen sollten hier zunächst die kostenlosen DataCamp Kurse wie z.B. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com/courses/free-introduction-to-r&#34;&gt;Introduction to R&lt;/a&gt; absolviert werden.
Zum anderen ist die Gruppe eine Art Langzeitgedächtnis der uns ermöglicht zu sehen
wer in welchem Umfang die DataCamp Schulungen genutzt hat, da hier die Nutzerzahl
(im Gegensatz zu unserem kostenpflichtigem DataCamp Gruppenaccount) nicht
limitiert ist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willst du kostenpflichtige DataCamp Kurse belegen, dann melde dich bitte bei
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrustl.github.io&#34;&gt;Michael Rustler&lt;/a&gt; persönlich oder per &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:michael.rustler@kompetenz-wasser.de&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;,
dann füge ich dich unserer kostenpflichtigen Gruppe hinzu und es können alle
DataCamp Kurse absolviert werden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sobald kein Bedarf oder längere Zeit keine Kurse absolviert werden können (z.B.
wegen Zeitmangel), bitte ebenfalls mit &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrustl.github.io&#34;&gt;Michael Rustler&lt;/a&gt;
persönlich oder per &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:michael.rustler@kompetenz-wasser.de&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt; Kontakt
aufnehmen, damit der Platz für weitere Lernwillige zur Verfügung steht.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
